What's going on everyone?
We are going to be going over some objection handling.
I've had a lot of people reach out with some different objections that sellers
are giving them, so I figured better put all the objections that I hear,
or at least the main ones, all in one place in exactly what order.
But I would say to it, so you guys know exactly what you can
say to these homeowners when you're talking to them. So I'm going to review
this document, with you guys, but you're going to have access to this.
Be able to check it out whenever you need to,
and you can kind of craft these as a text.
These are specifically for if you're talking to someone on the phone.
but you can easily make these into a text. So let's start from the
top. Wrong number. This isn't Mr.
Homeowner. Ah, gotcha. Well,
hey, I'm calling about the property over on X Street.
were you guys interested in selling that? Even when someone tells you that you
have the wrong number and that that's not the right homeowner.
I've had deals that I've gotten under contract after someone told me it was
the wrong number. A lot of times they're doing that because they don't recognize
your number calling them or one of various reasons and they're just trying to
tell you it's the wrong number and that's just a wall they're putting up,
because they think it's some solicitor calling them. So you can get past that
by continuing on with the conversation. You always want to be very conversational with
these people. I digress. Let's keep going. Objection.
I don't need any other options. Totally understand.
Just want to make sure, we're only creating win-win situations here.
so do you have another We'll them about five to ten minutes to talk
about the property, in your situation. If someone says,
I'll sell for the right price. That totally makes sense.
when you say the right price, is there a specific number in mind?
we want to always come to an agreement that makes sense for both parties.
If someone says, I'll sell for the right
price, is there a specific
number in mind?
there's that differentiate someone who doesn't do many deals or has never done a
deal with people that do, because they're willing to go the extra mile,
ask that extra question, push through the objection when someone says,
wrong number or not interested, and they can still get deals done that way.
So if we keep going. if someone just says, hey,
I'm not interested, or I changed my mind, that's funny you say that.
I had several people tell me that lately. In fact, the last two people
I've spoken to, said that they changed their mind or weren't interested because the
offers they've gotten have been too low. Is that why you're not interested?
So I'm just saying, just keeping it very conversational with them,
asking if the reason they're not interested is just because they've gotten low offers.
Sometimes other people that have given these people very low ball offers are the
people that ruin it for us. So we need to be able to push
past that objection and move forward.
Even when someone says, says they've changed their mind on selling because there's always
a reason why they changed their mind. And we want to get to the
bottom of that. A lot of times it's price. Sometimes it's other things.
We always want to find what that reason is.
if someone just says right off the bat,
make me an offer. My top talk track is typically Mr.
Homeowner. That's exactly it. That's exactly what, why I'm giving you a call today.
Now I can tell you that it's definitely not the first time someone has
called about the property. Let me tell you why this will be a little
different than the other calls you've had at the end of,
and do you see how I'm not reading exactly what this says?
I'm kind of putting my own personality into it. But I'm not reading verbatim.
You guys don't want to seem like you're reading off of a script.
You want to be able to just read through these, and talk to people
like it's just another person on the other end of the line.
So, at the end of the call today, after we talk about your property,
one of two things will happen. Either I'll come back with an approval.
I'll come an offer, or a denial with a reason.
I just need to ask you a few questions. Does that sound fair?
So you're telling them you're either going to approve the property and you're going
to give them an offer after you ask them some questions.
Or you're going to say, hey, that's not going to fit for us,
and you're going to give them a reason why. so, as long as you
make it sound like, hey, it's going to be a quick conversation,
I just need to know a few things. a lot of times they're going
to want to continue that conversation just so they can hear what that number
is, even if it's just out of curiosity, and that's totally okay.
if someone says, that's none of your business, I hear that a lot.
The only reason I ask is because it's not my business. the sellers have
other needs, that we're able to help out with, such as letting them stay
in the property, for some time after we close,
so they have time to, you know, hire movers,
and so you're not rushed leaving the property.
That's something we call post-occupancy. the next objection,
why? or, what does that have to do with anything?
Someone, might ask you if you ask them about a wash on their property,
or if it's in a floodplain, or if there's any easements or anything.
I just want to make sure I understand your situation to be sure,
that we're going to be able to give you, a good offer, and that
it's going to be a good fit for each other. So, anything,
that they say, why do I have to give you that information,
or why do you need to know that, it's just, hey, I want to
be able to make you the best offer I can, and I just need
to know the answer to this in order to do that.
Does that sound fair? I always end with something like,
does that sound fair? because when we're not asking too much,
saying, does that sound fair, usually kind of calms the other person down a
little bit, and they're like, okay, that makes sense why they would need to
know that. as we move on, I need to speak with my lawyer.
This is something you might hear from some of these higher-end,
sellers. They might have an attorney that needs to look over the contract.
I always tell them, absolutely, what we found that works best,
is for you and I to go over the contract line-by-line together,
so that when you send it to your attorney, you have all the questions
prepared. do you have ten minutes to go over that agreement now?
I like to try to go over the agreement now. I like with them
before they send it to their attorney. That way we can get anything changed
that they need or any questions that they have answered prior to it getting
to their attorney. If they say no,
I still want to just send it straight to my attorney, I usually try
and help them out and say, hey, no problem, I can make it easier
for you, just send me your attorney's email and I'll send it over to
them right now and that's what I'll do. Next off,
I need to think about it. So this is usually early in the call,
someone just says, ah, I just need to think about it. My response is
typically, hey, I totally get that, it's a big decision.
Normally when people tell me they need a little bit time to about it,
it's because one of two things. Either they need more information or they just
aren't interested and want to tell me no.
Which is the case here? If they need to think about it,
there's usually a reason why. So we want to make sure that we get
to the bottom of that. And there's some other notes here.
That you guys can, refer to as well.
If we go on to, I want the price Zillow says my home is
worth. So if someone says,
I want the Zillow price for what my home is worth,
Mr. Homeowner, I totally understand. And actually,
I hear this often. Let me explain what this estimate really means.
It's a guesstimate on what the property is actually worth.
How it works is they take the average price per square foot in the
area and they multiply it by the size of your home.
So what this doesn't include is all the different factors like number of new
builds and remodels that have way higher price per square foot that happen in
the neighborhood that sometimes can inflate what the guesstimate number is.
And then, I don't have this in here, but if you guys want to
add, a lot of times I tell people, hey, Zillow actually tried to start
a home buying program. And within about two to four to three months,
if you look it up online, they almost went out of business because they
were losing so much money because their algorithm was so off.
so, I hate to tell you, Mr. Seller, but, that is just the reality
with Zestimate. It's not always accurate. Next one.
I got another question. My talk track is usually,
oh great, it must have been something that you didn't like,
if you haven't accepted it, otherwise you would have signed that contract.
can you share what that offer was with me or forward you whatever they
gave you? Sometimes they might not want to do that,
but ask them about what the terms were.
Ask them what the purchase price was. If they can't answer these questions right
away, or they kind of fumble through it,
they probably didn't get another offer, and that's a good indicator that they're bluffing
you. next objection, you called me, give me a number.
Right, I hear that a lot. Here's the thing,
I did not come up with the numbers, my only job was to speak
with you and gather the information, and I can take it back to the
underwriters and fight for a number that works for you, so,
what do you feel like a fair price would be for me to take
back to them? Put it back on them, right after they ask you that.
and then, finally, I have a higher offer,
I always say, hey, I hear that all the time,
too, can you explain what that offer is to me? Give them the chance
to explain what that offer is, if they don't want to give much information,
just say, okay, can you tell me the price in terms,
that way, if I can't match it or beat it,
I'll move on, you won't hear from me again, or,
if you give me the terms and price, I'll bring it back to my
team and see if we can beat that, and if we can,
then we'd love to work together. so that is a brief overview of,
a lot of the objections that we hear on a day-to-day basis,
so, thank you. I hope it helps,
and I just want to implore all of you,
please, please, please, just be very conversational with these people.
Don't feel like you have to read off of a script every single time.
Make it part of your, personality. Put your personality into that script when you're
talking to these people. I know it can be nerve-wracking early on,
talking to these sellers, but the more conversational you keep it,
and the more casual you keep it with them, the better it's going to
be for you. So, good luck to everyone, and hope this document helps.